Life is waiting.
The Terminal is a comedy, drama film directed by Steven Spielberg.
An Eastern European tourist unexpectedly finds himself stranded in JFK
airport, and must take up temporary residence there.
Viktor Navorski, played by Tom Hanks.
Amelia Warren, played by Catherine Zeta-Jones.
Frank Dixon, played by Stanley Tucci.
Mulroy, played by Chi McBride.
Enrique Cruz, played by Diego Luna.
Thurman, played by Barry Shabaka Henley.
The Terminal is a 2004 American comedy-drama film produced and directed by Steven
Spielberg and starring Tom Hanks, Catherine Zeta-Jones and Stanley Tucci.
The film is about an Eastern European man who is stuck in New York's John F.
Kennedy Airport terminal when he is denied entry to the United States, but is
unable to return to his native country because of a military coup.
The film is partially inspired by the true story of Mehran Karimi Nasseri who lived in
Terminal 1 of Paris Charles de Gaulle Airport, France, from 1988 to 2006.
After finishing Catch Me If You Can (2002), Spielberg decided to direct The Terminal because he
wanted to make a film "that could make us laugh and cry and feel good about the world".
As no suitable airport was willing to provide their facilities, an entire working set was built inside a large hangar at the LA/Palmdale Regional
Airport, with the customs hall, offices and most of the film's exterior shots filmed at the Montreal–Mirabel International Airport.
The film was released in North America by DreamWorks Pictures on June 18, 2004, to generally
positive reviews and was a commercial success, earning $219 million worldwide.
The film explores themes of new york city, friendship,
marriage proposal, airport, stewardess.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.